<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <title>OSGi Development and Building</title>
    <author email="frei@inf.ethz.ch">Andreas Frei</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
  
    <section name="OSGi Development and Building">
    <p>
    	Using this maven-osgi-plugin to build OSGi bundles
    	is not the only way to do it, see <a href="http://www.knopflerfish.org/programming.html#custom">Knopflerfish</a>
    	which uses ant to build bundles.
    </p>
    <p>
    	By using this plugin you can benefit from the maven infrastructure
    	with site generation and the many generated reports. Great advantages
    	are also the simple project.xml files and dependencies declarations.
    	We also discovered,	when using maven in general, a stronger 
    	separation of packages in <b>APIs, and Implementations</b>. The structure 
    	of the code gets much clearer for new developers and writing 
    	documentation as xdocs or javadoc gets fun.
    </p>
    <p>
    	OSGi is predestinated with its many different services for such
    	a project management tool like maven. Every service defined in
    	OSGi can be generated into its own bundle and therefore also a
    	package for maven. Whereas OSGi supports the API different 
    	implementations for the framework and services are already available.
    	A developer or company who doesn't want to compile against
    	a concreate implementation could only use the API of OSGi and
    	later on at deployment/test use a concreate implementation.
    	Unfortunately the separation into APIs and Implementation
    	has not yet progressed or started for OSGi.
    </p>
    <p>
    	The OSGi Alliance supports the free available API for the
    	framework and services but packages it into one big .jar file.
    	To overcome this problem we propose and support on this
    	page the project.xml files for the free available OSGi-API. 
    	Maybe one time the API packages could be made available to 
    	<a href="http://www.ibiblio.org/maven">ibiblio/maven</a> but the 
    	licensing is not clear about this, in case you have more information
    	about the license please inform us.
    </p>
    
    <subsection name="Getting started with mavenized OSGi bundles">
    <p>
    	You are not required to set up this full infrastructure if you
    	only want to build some basic bundles, test the plugin or when your
    	are happy with another buildsystem. In case you are going to use
    	many services from OSGi we recommend to take the time for installation.
    	When you <a href="install.html">installed</a> this plugin, you already
    	got the OSGi framework API which you can find in your local maven 
    	repository under .maven/repository/osgi/jars/osgi-framework-1.2.jar.
    </p>
    <p>
    	To mavenize OSGi four steps are required:
    	<ol>
    		<li>install the <a href="install.html">maven-osgi-plugin</a></li>
    		<li>download and unpackage the osgi.jar from the 
    			<a href="http://osgi.org/resources/spec_download.asp">OSGi Alliance</a>,</li>
    		<li>download and unpackage the <a href="resources/osgi_mavenize.tar">osgi_mavenize.tar</a> 
    			<b>inside</b> the previously unpackaged osgi.jar directory,</li>
    		<li>mavenize one of your OSGi implementation.</li>
    	</ol>
    	
    	<p>
    		Currently we only support a view of the OSGi services in maven.
    		In case the one you need is missing inform 
    		<a href="mailto:frei@inf.ethz.ch">us</a> and we will
    		added it to the osgi_mavenize.tar or send us the project.xml.
    	</p>
    	
    	<p>
    		To mavenize an OSGi implementation we currently support following
    		implementation. Send us a link in case yours is also mavenized
    		or you have a similar osgi_impl_mavenize.tar.
    	</p>
    	
    	<table>
    	
    		<tr><th>OSGi Implementation</th><th>mavenize.tar</th><th>Description</th><th>supported services</th></tr>
    		
    		<tr>
    			<td><a href="http://knopflerfish.org">Knopflerfish</a></td>
    			<td><a href="resources/osgi_kf_mavenize.tar">osgi_kf_mavenize.tar</a></td>
    			<td>unpack inside the knopflerfish root folder, call inside kf/osgi dir maven</td>
    			<td>framework</td>
    		</tr>
    		
    		<tr>
    			<td><a href="http://oscar-osgi.sourceforge.net">OSCAR</a></td>
    			<td></td>
    			<td></td>
    			<td></td>
    		</tr>
    		
    		<tr>
    			<td><a href="http://www-306.ibm.com/software/wireless/smf/">IBM SMF</a></td>
    			<td></td>
    			<td></td>
    			<td></td>
    		</tr>
    		
    		<tr>
    			<td><a href="http://www.eclipse.org/equinox">Eclipse-Equinox</a></td>
    			<td></td>
    			<td></td>
    			<td></td>
    		</tr>
    		
    	</table>
    </p>
    
    </subsection>
    	
    </section>
    
 </body>
</document>
